<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael Raypold</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michael Raypold</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 16:20:58 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Influential Books</title>
      <link>/posts/influential-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 16:20:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/influential-books/</guid>
      <description>The following are a few of the books which I’ve found impactful in my day-to-day thinking, work and career development since graduating from university.
Measure What Matters: How Google, Bono, and the Gates Foundation Rock the World with OKRs Takeaways:
 OKRs are incredibly valuable in their ability to focus an organization or team, but poorly constructed OKRs can do more damage than good. Clear goals and measurable results are a focus mechanism that help an organization scale out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laravel Queues in Production</title>
      <link>/posts/laravel-queues-in-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 16:58:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/laravel-queues-in-production/</guid>
      <description>The Laravel queue and event system is one of the most powerful features of the framework and indispensable if you want to build a modern web application.
The queue provides a performant means to run background tasks that don’t block your HTTP lifecycle, allowing you to serve up a responsive application to your customers. Typically, you would use the queue to send emails, collect metrics or generate reports, amongst a number of other tasks that are either time consuming, prone to failure or can be done in an asynchronous manner that don’t impede the user’s workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laravel Distributed Maintenance Mode</title>
      <link>/posts/laravel-distributed-maintenance-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 06:50:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/laravel-distributed-maintenance-mode/</guid>
      <description>The Laravel maintainers have begun to invest more time in providing features and tooling for managing Laravel in a distributed environment.
Laravel 5.4 modified the withoutOverlapping() option for kernel tasks (PR #16196) to use the cache to create a lock and prevent overlapping scheduled tasks across instances.
Laravel Horizon makes it easier to monitor and maintain Laravel powered Redis queues in both a distributed and single instance deployment.
Laravel 5.5 includes TrustedProxy so that you can more easily place your application behind a load balancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 06:50:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>A tech lead in Victoria, BC who is passionate about building teams, products and a company.
When I&amp;rsquo;m not at work, you&amp;rsquo;ll find me outside on the patio reading a book or cycling.
Some Recent Books I&amp;rsquo;ve Enjoyed  Staff Engineer: Leadership beyond the management track Turn the Ship Around!: A True Story of Turning Followers into Leaders The Manager&amp;rsquo;s Path: A Guide for Tech Leaders Navigating Growth and Change An Elegant Puzzle: Systems of Engineering Management What You Do Is Who You Are: How to Create Your Business Culture The Everything Store: Jeff Bezos and the Age of Amazon Super Pumped: The Battle for Uber Measure What Matters Powerful: Building a Culture of Freedom and Responsibility Railroader: The Unfiltered Genius and Controversy of Four-Time CEO Hunter Harrison Bad Blood: Secrets and Lies in a Silicon Valley Startup The Hard Thing About Hard Things: Building a Business When There Are No Easy Answers  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
